Let's get to it and
silence this irritating rapper.
(水月)さっさと その耳障りな
ダジャレヤローを➡
黙らせてしまおうよ！
(サスケ)そのつもりだ！
I intend to.
It's not irritating...
♪♪(キラービー)「ダジャレじゃねえ
オシャレなライムじゃ コノヤロー アゥ アエー！」
It's cool rhythms and rhymes.
You fool! Ah! Yeah!!
(香燐)なんか マジ ムカツクな！
He's really... irritating!
He's got zero rapping talent!
コイツ ラップの才能ねえじゃん！
What?! You fool! You jerk!
♪♪「何だと！ コノヤロー バカヤロー！」
Will you shut up?!
うるせえ 黙れ！
The pain in my chest, baby!
Is like from your kicking, yo!
You're not running now, come on!
We're settling this score
'til I'm kicking, YEAH!
RHYME NOTES
I'm feeling good right now.
今は気分がいいぜ
最高のライムが書けた センキュー。
Just came up with
the greatest rhyme.
Thank you.
♪♪「だから 遊んでやるぜ
バカヤロー ベイベー！」
That's why I'll play with you...
You foolish baby!
Watch out, Sasuke!
This guy's used to handling blades!
気をつけて サスケ
コイツ 刀を使い慣れてる!!
ただの忍じゃないよ。
He's no ordinary ninja!
フフフ…。
オレ様のフック 感じさせてやるぜ！
I'll give you a taste of my hook.
i realise the screaming pain
hearing loud in my brain
but i'm going straight ahead with the scar
I should just get over it and I should just stop feeling it
wasurete shimaeba ii yo kanjinaku nacchaeba ii
and so I covered my grazed heart
surimuita kokoro ni futa wo shitan da
I don't care if I'm hurt 'cause I don't feel pain anymore
kizutsuitatte heki da yo mou itami wa nai kara ne
all while you limped on while dragging your feet behind you
sono ashi wo hikizuri nagara mo
I had lost sight of myself
miushinatta jibun jishin ga
which had crumbled loudly to the ground
oto wo taete kuzureteita
but then I realised it was just the sound of the wind...
kizukeba kaze no oto dake ga
I came here to tell you something following my deep scars
tsutae ni kita yo kizuato wo tadotte
before I am completely crushed by this vast world
sekai ni oshitsubusarete shimau mae ni
do you remember that sky of tears
oboeteru kana namida no sora wo
that pain protected you for me
ano itami ga kimi no koto wo mamotte kureta
that pain is always protecting you
sono itami ga itsumo kimi wo mamotterunda
can you hear me so am i
The Eight-Tails vs Sasuke
な…。
なんだ？ あの構えは。
Wha--?
What's with that stance?
サスケ！ 大丈夫か!?
Sasuke! Are you all right?!
なんだよ あの動き…
太刀筋が まるでよめない。
What's with those moves?
I can't read through
his line of attack.
《千鳥…。
Chidori?
ガード不可の千鳥刀か》
He plans to use
his indefensible Chidori Blade!
何!? ガードした!?
What?! He countered it?!
《アイツも
チャクラ流しを使えるのか!?》
He can stream his chakra too?!
♪♪「マイ！ 蝶のように舞い！」
Float... Float like a butterfly...!
♪♪「八尾 蜂のように刺す」
Eight-Tails! Sting like a bee!
サスケ!!
Sasuke!
♪♪「そして これでトドメ刺す！」
And this is the finishing sting!
《くっ… コイツも
ボクの苦手な雷遁を!?》
He also uses...
Lightning Style, which is my weakness.
サスケ！
Sasuke!
やばい。
This is bad...
ほら サスケ。
さっさと ウチに噛みつけ。
Here, Sasuke...
Hurry up and bite me!
ほら 早く。
Do it now!
あぁ～。
《雷遁を体に流して
攻撃の軌道をずらしたか。
He funneled the Lightning Style
through his body
and shifted the course of my attack.
致命傷は 避けたようだな。
He avoided a fatal injury...
で あの女がチャクラを吸わせて
回復させる能力か》
And... that woman possesses
the ability
to heal others by letting them
suck her chakra.
ハァ… ハァ…。
助かったぞ 香燐。
ああ…。
Thanks, Karin.
Sure...
サスケ ３人でやるよ。
Sasuke! Let's do this together!
はっきり言って この人
ムチャクチャ強いよね。
The fact is this guy is super strong.
殺さずってのは 考えず➡
We should go at him as if
we are trying to kill him, instead of not.
殺すつもりでいこう。
それで 死なない程度に
倒せるはずだよ。
That way we can probably take him
down without killing him.
こりゃあ バトルが長引きそうだぜ。
Looks like this battle is gonna drag on...
チェケラッチョ！
Check it out, yo!
かかったな。
Got you!
サスケ今だよ ボクごとやれ。
Sasuke, now! Just do the both of us!
千鳥！
Chidori!
(重吾)いない… どこだ？
Gone! Where is he?
♪♪「弱いくせに めんどくせえ」
So weak, yet so persistent...
♪♪「遊びは終わり
帰って 水割り イェ～」
I'm done playing,
now go home for some drinking! Yeah!
香燐！
わかってる！
- Karin!
- I know...
あそこだ！
Over there!
《感知タイプでもあるのか あの女》
That woman's also a sensory-type, eh?
しかたない。
Can't be helped...
８本目だ！ ウィ～!!
Going with the eighth tail.
《出たか…
同じだな あの時と…》
Here it comes...
It's the same as back then.
《ほぉ～
この８本目をかわしたのは➡
Hmm... He's the first to dodge
my eight-tails form
ブラザー以来だ》
since my brother.
クソッ！ そっちに！
Damn, he's going after the others!
♪♪「先に お前ら バラバラ」
First, you guys will be torn apart!
無事か！
あぁ… なんとかな。
Are you all right?
Yeah... more or less...
《確かに スピードも威力もある。
He definitely has speed and power.
だが 動きは直線的。
But he only moves in
a linear fashion.
この目なら
見切れないことはない。
My eyes should be able to
make them out.
香燐！ ヤツのチャクラを感じとって
行動を先読みしろ！
Karin! Read his chakra and
predict his movements!
ヤツの居場所は 常に把握して
オレに伝えるんだ！
Stay on him and keep me informed
of his location at all times!
それで 間に合うならな!!
That's if you can really keep up!
サスケ!!
Sasuke!
《その目 写輪眼！
Those eyes... The Sharingan!
Is this genjutsu?
幻術か… 体が動かない！》
I can't move my body.
うっ！
ラリアット!!
Lariat!
ウィ～!!
サスケ!!
Sasuke!
な… 何だよ？ これ…。
Wha--?!
What is this?
体の 首と胸の部分が➡
His neck and chest portion have
been blown off, organs and all.
内臓ごと ふっ飛んでる…。
ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…。
これは… もう…。
He's beyond our...
((君麻呂 : 彼は ボクの
生まれ変わりのような存在だ))
He is like my reincarnation.
待ってろ！
Hang in there!
香燐 いい オレがやる。
Karin, it's all right. I'll do it.
今のお前のチャクラじゃ 無理だろう。
The chakra you have now
can't deal with it.
何をする気だ!?
What do you intend to do?
サスケの体と同化して
オレのチャクラと 体を分け与える。
I'll distribute my body and chakra to
Sasuke by merging with him.
オレの呪印と適合できた
サスケの体なら できるはずだ。
Since his body was compatible with
my curse mark, it should work.
幻術を解くには
己のチャクラを乱して➡
In order to release the genjutsu,
I need a partner to disturb
my chakra and awaken me.
目を覚ましてくれる相棒が必要だ。
オレ様の相棒は オレの中の八尾。
My partner is
the Eight-Tails inside me.
尾獣をコントロールした人柱力に
幻術は効かねえ。
A genjutsu has no effect on
the Jinchuriki host,
which controls a Tailed Beast.
♪♪「お前らには 幻滅」
Your illusions I obliterate,
then you all I shall annihilate.
♪♪「そして お前ら 壊滅」
♪♪「人柱力である オレ様の本当の姿」
My true form of the Jinchuriki...
♪♪「それは怪物 それを見物
人柱変化 イエ～イ」
It's a monster, so watch it now,
Host Transformation, yeah...
♪♪「八尾でちびれ おチビ共」
Eight-Tails will make you pee your pants,
you lil' ants!
《このチャクラ… こんなのって
ありなのか？》
Such chakra...
Is this even possible?
これが 八尾。
牛とタコのバケモノ…。
That's the Eight-Tails?
それが ヤツの正体ってわけか。
An ox-octopus monster...
That's his true form?
♪♪「敵を刺す 敵刺すロングホーン」
To spear my foes,
my glorious longhorns!
ウィ～!!
《このチャクラ ありえない。
ここにいたら死ぬ！》
His chakra is off the scale...
重吾 まだなのか？
We'll die if we stay here!
Jugo, are you done yet?!
《よかった… サスケ》
気づいたか！
ほら さっさと起きろ。
Thank goodness... Sasuke...
You're conscious.
Come on, get up!
よし 重吾… え？
子供に？ なんで!?
All right, Jugo... Huh?!
重吾…。
He turned into a child?! Why?!
お前は死なせない。
君麻呂の形見だからな。
Jugo...
I won't let you die...
ほら早く！
２人とも逃げるぜ！
You're a memento of Kimimaro.
Come on! Hurry! We gotta run!
ウィ～!!
やっぱ 水遁系の忍だったか。
A Water-Style ninja... I knew it.
地の利を得たな!!
デヤ～！
ここは ボクがやる！
You have the advantage
of the terrain!
今のうちに逃げろ！
I'll take over from here!
Run while you can!
ウ～!!
水月…。
行くぞ サスケ。
Suigetsu...
ウオ～!!
Let's go, Sasuke.
《このボクが 何度も身を挺して
あんなヤツらをかばうなんてね》
Heh. Who would've thought...
that I'd end up sacrificing myself
to save their hides this often?
うお～!!
ここまでさせておいて 逃がすか!!
バカヤロー コノヤロー！
As if I'd let you get away after
what you've done, you fool, you jerk!
ウオ～!!
ヤバすぎるぞ アレ！
Th-That really doesn't look good.
まさか アレは キラービー様の…。
何です？ 先輩。
Could that be Killer Bee-sama's?!
行くぞ！
はい！
Wh-What is it, Senpai?!
- Let's go!
- Yes, sir!
こ… これは！
Th-That's...!
キラービー様
なんで 八尾のお姿に？
Killer Bee-sama...
あれほど
雷影様から止められていたのに。
Why has he transformed into
the Eight-Tails?!
And after all that lecturing
from the Raikage-sama...
よく見てください！
誰かと戦ってます！
Look closely!
He's battling someone!
あの衣… 暁か？
Those robes...
アレが ユギトを連れ去った…。
Are they the Akatsuki?
The ones who kidnapped Yugito?
水月が こんなに…。
クソ… 逃げきれないぞ。
Suigetsu is wasted... Damn it!
どうすんだよ？
We can't get away... What'll we do?!
((ほら サスケ
さっさと ウチに噛みつけ！
Here, Sasuke.
Hurry up and bite me!
お前は死なせない。
君麻呂の形見だからな。
I won't let you die...
(ここは ボクがやる！
今のうちに逃げろ！))
You're a memento of Kimimaro.
I'll take over from here!
Run while you can!
ウィ～！
(香燐)くるぞ！
He's coming!
《天照！》
Amaterasu!
うわぁ～！
《こ… これが サスケの言っていた
消えない黒炎か！》
S-So those are the inextinguishable
black flames Sasuke spoke of!
グオ～！
《す… すげえ》
A-Awesome!
ぐあ～！
あっ…。
あ～っ！
香燐 走れ！
Karin, run!
あっ…。
クソ 黒炎が…。
香燐は もうダメだ。
オレたちも巻きぞえを食う前に➡
Damn! The black flames!
It's too late for Karin.
ここを いったん離れる！
待て 重吾。
We need to get away before
we get caught too!
ダメだ！
- Wait, Jugo.
- No!
《香燐…》
Karin!
うわっ… あ～！
こ… これは…。
Wh-What?
重吾 香燐を早く！
Jugo! Get Karin! Hurry!
やはり 黒炎が消えている…。
どういうことだ サスケ！
The black flames are extinguished...
What's going on, Sasuke?
《消せた…
あの天照の黒炎を…。
I was able to extinguish
the black flames of Amaterasu.
これが この万華鏡の瞳力なのか。
Are these the visual powers
of my Mangekyo Sharingan?!
それなら…》
In which case...
八尾…
かろうじて生きているようだ。
The Eight-Tails...
It seems he's barely alive.
これで 八尾を殺さずにすんだ…
さっさと連れていくぞ。
Then... we managed to take down
the Eight-Tails without killing him.
Let's grab him and go.
まさか…
あの キラービー様がやられた…。
No way...
Killer Bee-sama has been defeated?
そんな ウソでしょう…
助けますか？
I-It must be some mistake...
ヤツらは 暁のメンバーだ 早まるな。
Shall we rescue him?
They're Akatsuki members.
Don't be hasty.
ん… あれは！
何です!?
Huh?! That's...
うちはの家紋！
What is it?!
うちは？
オレたちは出しゃばるより➡
The Uchiha crest!
Uchiha?
すぐに雷影様に
報告したほうが賢明だ。
Rather than taking action ourselves,
we'd better get word to Lord Raikage!
弟がこんな目にあったとなったら
あの雷影様…。
If he hears what happened
to his younger brother...
黙ってませんね…。
Knowing Raikage-sama,
he won't be pleased at all.
だいぶ 体にきているようだな…。
You seem quite affected, physically.
大蛇丸の呪印も
なくなったあげく➡
Especially since, in addition to
losing Orochimaru's curse mark,
イタチ戦での傷も
癒えていなかったからな…。
you haven't quite healed from
your battle against Itachi.
あぁ… ここまで追い込まれるとは
思ってもみなかったがな。
Yeah...
Though I really didn't expect
we'd have such a fight on our hands.
だが これで…。
But now...
here are the answers of the path
koko ni aru no wa kimi ga ima made erande michi no
you chose up till now, look and go on by yourself
kotae tachi yo hora jishin motte susumeba ii
it's very natural, like a rainbow over
totemo shizen na no amaeagari no
asphalt after a rainfall
asufaruto ni niji ga kakaru you ni
a lonely wind blew and
lonely kaze ga fuite
a feeling dawned on me
feeling ki ga tsuita yo
there are any answers anywhere
kotae wo doko ni mo nai kedo
call me, I got it already
call me wakatteru wa
with you, we'll always
with you ai wa itsu mo
love each other
atae au mono
for you
I'm sure one day you will
kitto kimi wa itsu no hi ka
be able to fly in the sky
kono sora wo toberu hazu dakara
no matter how many times we've stumbled for you
nando tsumaizuta to shite mo for you
there's only one thing important
taisetsu na koto wa hitotsu
which is to dream
yumemiru koto
so at least keep your heart open
kokoro dake wa tozasanaide ite
Next Episode
I've been waiting for you all.
Katsuyu-sama!
What are you doing here?
It's an emergency.
The barrier to Mount Katsuragi
has been broken!
What?! Of the Tsuchigumo clan?
Time is of essence.
Under the secret treaty made
by the Third Hokage,
Team Seven will immediately
head out to the location
with Yamato-san as team captain.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Wanderer"
Wanderer
It's an all-new mission!
(ナツ)ぶわぁ～ ぶぇ～。